Guide to the Bernhard Knollenberg Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Correspondence (Chronological), 1560-1943; Series I; 5.5 linear feet (13 Boxes)
  - ADS, James Perry (tax collector); receipt for taxes from Joel Barlow, 1818 December 28 (Box 7, Folder 536)
  - ADS, Benjamin Williams; receipt for payment for candles by Peter Lanman, 1819 January 2 (Box 7, Folder 537)
  - ALS, Dr. L. Worcester to Alfred Ely regarding upcoming Board meeting and election, 1819 September 9 (Box 7, Folder 538)
  - ALS, Francis Wentworth Morton to Andrew Brimmer; trip across Alabama, death of sister, 1819 September 11 (Box 7, Folder 539)
  - ADS, James Perry (tax collector); receipt for taxes from Joel Barlow, 1819 December 20 (Box 7, Folder 540)
  - ADS, Henry W. Huntington (public notary); notarized I.O.U. from Spencer and Dunn, 1820 July 15 (Box 7, Folder 541)
  - DS, G. Lofland (auditor); receipt for $10.50 in taxes from Joel Barlow, 1820 December 29 (Box 7, Folder 542)
  - ALS, Robert G. Harper to N.A. Charlton, Esq, answer to request for help in gaining a promotion, 1821 March 19 (Box 7, Folder 543)
  - ALS, John Bell to Aaron White regarding sale of White's land. Photostat of Original, 1821 November 1 (Box 7, Folder 545)
  - DS, G. Lofland (aviator); receipt from Joel Barlow for taxes on land, 1821 December 29 (Box 7, Folder 546)
  - ALS, Nathaniel Silsbee to J. Nelson regarding Act of 1820, 1822 March 22 (Box 7, Folder 547)
  - ALS, J.T. Kirkland (President) to (?); invitation to exercises for theological students, 1822 August 10 (Box 7, Folder 548)
  - ALS, Thomas Jefferson to Mr. Mills; thanks for pamphlet on canals. Photostat of Original, 1822 September 25 (Box 7, Folder 549)
  - DS, R. Osborn (auditor); receipt for taxes from Joel Barlow, 1823 January 20 (Box 7, Folder 550)
  - ALS, Alex Proudfilt to Ebenezer Morton (Comptroller's Office), 1823 February 26 (Box 7, Folder 551)
  - DS, R. Osborn (auditor); receipt for taxes from Joel Barlow, 1823 December 29 (Box 7, Folder 552)
  - ALS, William Lyon to Col. Joseph Bennett; regarding U.S. Bank controversy, family matters, 1824 January 15 (Box 7, Folder 553)
  - ALS, Jed (?) (cousin) to Mary H. Lanman; family matters, her brother David, 1824 January 17 (Box 7, Folder 554)
  - DS, Charles Niven to Capt. Seymour--notice of election to fill office of Major, 1824 April 20 (Box 7, Folder 555)
  - ALS, Joseph Pickering to Samuel Lathrop; request to forward letter to Dr. Rice, 1824 May 20 (Box 7, Folder 556)
  - ALS, John Forsyth to (?) Smith; recommends a physican, 1824 June 2 (Box 7, Folder 557)
  - ALS, Wolcott Huntington to Col. John Trumbull; payment of bill, 1824 July 15 (Box 7, Folder 558)
  - ALS, Robert Troup (?) to Timothy Pickering regarding Adams, Gates, etc. Photostat of Original, 1824 October 12 (Box 7, Folder 559)
  - ALS, A.H. Everett to Joseph Blumst regarding political situation, 1824 October 28 (Box 7, Folder 560)
  - ALS, R. Stackton to (?); remitts two bills and requests record sent to Sheriff, 1824 December 18 (Box 7, Folder 561)
  - ALS, Lockhart to (?) regarding Quarterly Review, phrenology, 1825 December 14 (Box 7, Folder 562)
  - ALS, G. Potter to David Mann regarding letter from Count Rumford, 1826 January 2 (Box 7, Folder 563)
  - ALS, John Forsythe to T. Louthon, Minister to Spain, 1826 January 29 (Box 7, Folder 564)
  - ALS, J. Monroe to H. Howe regarding various business transactions, 1826 February 20 (Box 7, Folder 565)
  - ALS, Richard Rush (Att'y Gen'l 1814, minister to Gr. Britain, 1819) to David Holmes (Gov. of Mississippi) regarding Treasury report on silk, 1826 July 29 (Box 7, Folder 566)
  - ALS, Timothy Pickering to John Marshall (Chief Justice) regarding controversy with Justice Johnson over Pulaski. Photostat of Original, 1827 February 14 (Box 7, Folder 567)
  - ADS, Samuel Paire to Harriet Thomas regarding West Middle School District, 1827 May 22 (Box 7, Folder 568)
  - ALS, Joseph Story to Justice Thompson (Supreme Court) regarding trial and admissible evidence, 1827 September 17 (Box 7, Folder 569)
  - MS, Robert Troup, account of Conway's cabal-General Washington. Photostat of Original, 1827 October 26 (Box 7, Folder 570)
  - ALS, Benjamin Pritchard to Aaron White--regarding family health. Photostat of Original, 1827 December 6 (Box 7, Folder 571)
  - ALS, Daniel Webster to Mrs. Burgess regarding Webster's wife, health, 1827 December 9 (Box 7, Folder 572)
  - ALS, Gen. Winfield Scott to Col. William S. Hamilton; request for visit together and comments on Atkinson, 1827 December 12 (Box 7, Folder 573)
  - AMS, Diary of John. T. Plumrner's trip to Yale. Photostat of Original, 1827 (Box 7, Folder 574)
  - ALS, M. Sanford to John McLean; acceptance of invitation to dinner, 1828 March 29 (Box 7, Folder 575)
  - ALS, John Jacob Astor to W.L. Chancy; proposal for loan of $110,000, 1828 April 14 (Box 7, Folder 576)
  - ADS, Deed between Mr.&Mrs. William Brodway and Isaac Bambo, 1828 September 1 (Box 7, Folder 577)
  - DS, McDonald (attorney for plaintiff); complaint for circuit court--promissory note, 1829 April (Box 7, Folder 578)
  - ALS, E.W. Blake to James Goodrich--Eli Whitney Estate. Photostat of Original, 1829 December 12 (Box 7, Folder 580)
  - Sales agreement from Sarah Johnson to Abner Bowen, 1829 (Box 16)
  - ADS,(?) Jennings to William Davis; request for information for court case, 1830 February 20 (Box 7, Folder 582)
  - ALS, W.H. Seward to Lee & Davis (tailors); request for coat and pantallons, 1830 December 13 (Box 7, Folder 584)
  - ALS, (?) to Bishop Alexander Jolly. Photostat of Original, 1830 (Box 7, Folder 585)
  - ALS, Lewis Cass to Jacob Burnet; recommendation of young man for appointment, 1831 January 2 (Box 7, Folder 586)
  - ALS, General John Armstrong to Jared Sparks--discussion of Gen. Gates' military character. Photostat of Original, 1831 December 4 (Box 7, Folder 587)
  - ALS, Robert Loomis to Daulphin Count of Sail County regarding petition of Richard Walter, 1832 February 2 (Box 7, Folder 588)
  - ALS, Son to Mrs. Jesse Pratt regarding cholera epidemic, 1832 July 11 (Box 7, Folder 589)
  - ALS, J.G. Bates to Edward E. Dehaven regarding papers on temperance. With etching of North Hampton, 1832 August 4 (Box 7, Folder 590)
  - ALS, Sec. of War (?) to Maj. General Alexander Mucomb; directions to report on organization of army, 1833 August 30 (Box 7, Folder 593)
  - ALS, Samuel Baker to Rev. Bernard Whitman regarding possible future plans, 1833 October 7 (Box 7, Folder 594)
  - ALS, John Ballow to Rev. Bernard Whitman regarding theological issues and questions, 1834 January 30 (Box 7, Folder 595)
  - ALS, B.F. Butler to W.C. Little; question about payment of bill, 1834 February 1 (Box 7, Folder 596)
  - ALS, Nathan Willis to James T. Austin (Attorney General of Mass.) concerning debt due State, 1835 January 26 (Box 7, Folder 597)
  - ALS, John Gibson Lockhart to (?); cheque for paper on Heine, 1835 February 18 (Box 7, Folder 598)
  - ALS, John Gibson Lockhart to (?); cheque for book by Meyer), 1835 April 22 (Box 7, Folder 599)
  - ALS, John Gibson Lockhart to Haywood; cheque for book on gastronomy, 1835 July 1 (Box 7, Folder 600)
  - ALS, W.L. Marcy to Geo. Sullivan, president of American Institute regarding Marcy's connection with Institute, 1835 November 23 (Box 7, Folder 601)
  - ALS, Robert W. Weir to Robert Gilmour concerning art work requested by Gilmour, 1835 December 27 (Box 7, Folder 602)
  - List of Bishops consecrated by months (Sep 1795-Sep 1835) (Box 7, Folder 603)
  - ADS, John Forsyth (Sec. of State) to Hon. Smith Thompson; notice of appointment of Taney, 1836 March 23 (Box 7, Folder 604)
  - ALS, Edward Livingston to Monsieur Hottinguer regarding political and family affairs, 1836 May 7 (Box 7, Folder 605)
  - ALS, John Gibson Lockhart to Haywood: postponement of dinner, 1836 May 14 (Box 7, Folder 606)
  - ALS, John Gibson Lockhart to Haywood; question about dinner with Murray, 1836 July 7 (Box 7, Folder 608)
  - ALS, Joseph Trumbull to [?] regarding spring election, 1837 March 13 (Box 7, Folder 609)
  - ALS, John Gibson Lockhart to Haywood; anti-women critics, 1837 April (Box 7, Folder 610)
  - ALS, Henry Baldwin to B. Appleton; draft for balance of account, 1837 June 3 (Box 7, Folder 611)
  - Photostat of letter and manuscript from John Armstrong to Jared Sparks regarding life of General Kosciusko (Rev. War), 1837 August (Box 7, Folder 612)
  - ALS, Major M.J. Terryn [?] to Capt. E.B. Robinson; refers to inability to raise troops for Robinson, suggests he recruit his own, 1837 September 22 (Box 7, Folder 613)
  - ALS, Lucy Barrett to Nathanaiel B. Cook; conflict between English and Canadians, 1837 November 28 (Box 7, Folder 614)
  - ALS, Lewis Cass to Virgil Maxcy, 1837 December 28 (Box 7, Folder 615)
  - ALS, J.S. Worcester to [?] regarding evaluation of Adams, 1838 March 19 (Box 8, Folder 616)
  - ALS, William Jones Hoppin (founder of Century Club) to Mrs. Caroline Street regarding family and literary matters, 1838 May 30 (Box 8, Folder 617)
  - ALS, Lewis Cass to Col. Aspinwall regarding food stuff, quantity, 1838 September 11 (Box 8, Folder 618)
  - ALS, Edward Everett to Gen. H.A.S. Dearborn; private information about formation of New guard, 1838 October 17 (Box 8, Folder 619)
  - ALS, Gov. W.H. Seward to Alvah Hunt regarding Chenango Canal, 1838 November 20 (Box 8, Folder 620)
  - ALS, Thurlow Weed to Alvah Hunt; congratulations on election, 1838 November 30 (Box 8, Folder 621)
  - Letters to Alvah Hunt Transcribed from originals in this collection by James M, Banner, Y'57 for term paper, 1838 November 30- 1850 (Box 8, Folder 622)
  - ALS, [?] J Johnson to Gen. Clemen; acceptance to attend cornerstone ceremony for War monument, 1839 September 8 (Box 8, Folder 623)
  - ALS, John Gibson Lockhart to Haywood; revision on articles, 1839 October 16 (Box 8, Folder 624)
  - ALS, Thurlow Weed to Alvah Hunt; regarding plans for Chenango, 1839 October 19 (Box 8, Folder 625)
  - ALS, Thurlow Weed to Alvah Hunt; confirmation of letter of Oct.19, 1839, 1839 October 22 (Box 8, Folder 626)
  - ALS, John Gibson Lockhart to Hayward; Gleig's Travels, Webster's speeches, 1839 November 7 (Box 8, Folder 627)
  - ALS, John Gibson Lockhart to Hayward regarding proposed History, 1840 February (Box 8, Folder 628)
  - ALS, Lewis Cass to E.T. Throop; possibility of war, 1840 April 22 (Box 8, Folder 629)
  - ALS, Mrs. C. Harrison to sister Juliet regarding trip to New York, conduct with men, etc, 1840 July 19 (Box 8, Folder 630)
  - DS, Martin Van Buren; pardon for Andrew Jackson Loftis, 1840 August 3 (Box 8, Folder 631)
  - ALS, John Gibson Lockhart to Hayward; leaving town for a few days, 1840 August 29 (Box 8, Folder 632)
  - ALS, Thurlow Weed to Alvah Hunt regarding Chenango land, Seward's possible election, 1840 September 24 (Box 8, Folder 633)
  - ALS, John Gibson Lockhart to Hayward; cheque for "P.G. on Music", 1840 September 28 (Box 8, Folder 634)
  - ALS, John Gibson Lockhart to Hayward; Lord Aberdeen's request, 1840 October 26 (Box 8, Folder 635)
  - ALS, Alvah Hunt to W.N. Seward & answer; attempt to visit, reminder of railroad, 1840 November 18 (Box 8, Folder 636)
  - ALS, Thurlow Weed to Alvah Hunt; invitation to dinner, 1840(?) (Box 8, Folder 637)
  - ALS, Butler to S. Thompson & newspaper clipping; refers to clipping about Supreme Court, 1840 December 24 (Box 8, Folder 638)
  - ALS, William H. Seward to Alvah Hunt; agreement with Hunt's plans, 1841 June 2 (Box 8, Folder 639)
  - ALS, William H. Seward to Alvah Hunt; asks opinion on appointment of Rawson Balcom, 1841 June 29 (Box 8, Folder 640)
  - ALS, John Gibson Lockhart to Haywood; articles on venables of Russia, 1841 July 25 (Box 8, Folder 641)
  - ALS, Thurlow Weed to Alvah Hunt; recent news about railroad transactions, 1841 September 10 (Box 8, Folder 642)
  - ALS, John Gibson Lockhart to Hayward. "The 30 Physiologies", 1841 October 14 (?) (Box 8, Folder 643)
  - ALS, Sullivan Seward to Alvah Hunt; urgent request for nomination for inspector of turnpikes, 1841 October 25 (Box 8, Folder 644)
  - ALS, John Gibson Lockhart to Hayward; various articles proposed, 1841 October 26 (Box 8, Folder 645)
  - ALS, Millard Fillmore to Alvah Hunt; comments on Senate matters, Tyler, Weed, 1841 December 2 (Box 8, Folder 646)
  - ALS, Daniel Webster to Alvah Hunt regarding Levi Butler, 1842 March 21 (Box 8, Folder 647)
  - ALS, Bishop Hughes to (?); congratulatory-success over enemies, 1842 March 23 (Box 8, Folder 648)
  - ALS, George Peter Vanwyck to his parents, Dr. T.C. Vanwyck. Description of travels, etc, 1842 May 8 (Box 8, Folder 649)
  - ALS, John Gibson Lockhart to Hayward; too ill to work on Quarterly Review, 1842 June 1 (Box 8, Folder 650)
  - ALS, John Gibson Lockhart to Hayward; anticipation of physiologies, 1842 July 29 (Box 8, Folder 651)
  - ALS, Benjamin Fitzpatrick to Charles McDonald (Gov. of Ga.); demands refused by Georgia, 1842 July 30 (Box 8, Folder 652)
  - ALS, A. Conkling to Smith Thompson regarding bankruptcy information, 1842 September 13 (Box 8, Folder 653)
  - ALS, Thurlow Weed to Alvah Hunt; pleasure at present state of affairs, 1842 September 29 (Box 8, Folder 654)
  - ALS, Thurlow Weed to Alvah Hunt; problems with rail-road fights, elections, 1842 October 20 (Box 8, Folder 655)
  - ALS, Thurlow Weed to Alvah Hunt; failures in New York, 1842 October 27 (Box 8, Folder 656)
  - ALS, John Gibson Lockhart to Hayward; Urges Hayward to interject "morality", 1842 December 29 (Box 8, Folder 657)
  - ALS, T. Hartley Crawford to Myles (?); report on claims of Edward Harrick, 1842 December 30 (Box 8, Folder 658)
  - ALS, W.H. Seward to Alvah Hunt; state printer controversy, 1843 January 15 (Box 8, Folder 659)
  - ALS, Thurlow Weed to Alvah Hunt regarding Maroy-VanBuren controversies, 1843 January 20 (Box 8, Folder 660)
  - ALS, Seward to Alvah Hunt; Weed's loss of power, Whig Congress, 1843 January 25 (Box 8, Folder 661)
  - ALS, Ben Butler to Hugh S. Logare; regarding court decisions, 1843 January 25 (Box 8, Folder 662)
  - ALS, Chief Justice Taney to Smith Thompson; progress of Supreme Court cases, 1843 March 15 (Box 8, Folder 663)
  - ALS, Anderson to A.P. Upshur; application to be agent for preservation of ship timber, 1843 March 30 (Box 8, Folder 664)
  - ALS, Thurlow Weed to Alvah Hunt; present situations of friends and acquaintances, 1843 April 5 (Box 8, Folder 665)
  - ALS, Thurlow Weed to Alvah Hunt; concerning proposed trip to Europe, 1843 May 24 (Box 8, Folder 666)
  - ALS, William Seward to Alvah Hunt; possible Presidential candidates, 1843 May 31 (Box 8, Folder 667)
  - ALS, Wendell Philips to Rev. J. Pierpont; letter of introduction for Mr. Clark, 1843 June 2 (Box 8, Folder 668)
  - Typed copy of letter; Samuel King to John King warning of dangers of "evil ways.", 1843 June 25 (Box 8, Folder 670)
  - AMS, S.W. Williams (professor); "History of Mount Auburn',", 1843 (Box 8, Folder 671)
  - ALS, Thurlow Weed to Alvah Hunt; defeat of Spencer, South's tariff demands, 1844 February 8 (Box 8, Folder 672)
  - DS, John Tyler (President); delay of execution of David Babe, 1844 February 27 (Box 8, Folder 673)
  - ALS, Thurlow Weed to Alvah Hunt; political conditions in Conn, Md, and Washington, 1844 March 1 (Box 8, Folder 674)
  - ALS, Thurlow Weed to Alvah Hunt; tariff fight, 1844 March 12 (Box 8, Folder 675)
  - ALS, Anson Gleason to sister Abby Lanman; thanks for sympathy note, 1844 March 16 (Box 8, Folder 676)
  - ALS, John Gibson Lockhart to Hayward; velvet gown, acquaintance with Lyndhurst, 1844 March 21 (Box 8, Folder 677)
  - ALS, W. Hunt to Alvah Hunt; Texas issue & tariffs, 1844 April 4 (Box 8, Folder 678)
  - ALS, Thurlow Weed to Alvah Hunt; Webster's problems and split of Loco-focus, 1844 May 11 (Box 8, Folder 679)
  - ALS, Thurlow Weed to Alvah Hunt; possible candidates for Canal Commission, 1844 August 22 (Box 8, Folder 680)
  - ALS, Thurlow Weed to Alvah Hunt; bad prospects for upcoming election, 1844 October 11 (Box 8, Folder 681)
  - ALS, Marcus Morton to B.J. Pease; Boston clique agitation, 1844 December 24 (Box 8, Folder 682)
  - TLS, John Gibson Lockhart to Abraham Hayward; regarding disagreement. Photostat of Original and typed copy, 1845 March 3 (Box 8, Folder 683)
  - DS, James Polk (President); Directive to affix seal to letter to King of Sardinia, 1845 September 3 (Box 8, Folder 684)
  - DS, To the Senate from Missouri citizens protesting refusal to confirm nomination of Silas Reed, 1845 (ca.) (Box 8, Folder 685)
  - ALS, Thurlow Weed to Alvah Hunt; strife between factions, 1846 January 6 (Box 8, Folder 686)
  - TLS, Jackson King to Thacker Lenelton; recent events in family, 1846 January 18 (Box 8, Folder 687)
  - ALS, Thurlow Weed to Alvah Hunt; against Seward's nomination, 1846 February 23 (Box 8, Folder 689)
  - ALS, Thurlow Weed to Alvah Hunt; break among opponents, 1846 March 12 (Box 8, Folder 690)
  - ALS, Horace Greeley to Alvah Hunt; suit for libel concerning Hunt's article, 1846 April 15 (Box 8, Folder 691)
  - ALS, Thurlow Weed to Alvah Hunt; Hunkers, Caucus, 1846 May 27 (Box 8, Folder 692)
  - ALS, George Grote to G. Stacey concerning printing of pamphlet, 1846 June 10 (Box 8, Folder 693)
  - ALS, C.C. Felton to George S. Hillard; thank you, brief comments on Lamb, 1846 September 24 (Box 8, Folder 694)
  - ALS, Thurlow Weed to Alvah Hunt; rising supporter of Hunkers, 1846 October 15 (Box 8, Folder 695)
  - ALS, Thurlow Weed to Alvah Hunt; hatred towards Dickinson and Birdsall, 1846 October 19 (Box 8, Folder 696)
  - ALS, Thurlow Weed to Alvah Hunt; Broome matter, 1846 October 21 (Box 8, Folder 697)
  - ALS, Horace Greeley to Philip B. Prindle; copy sent to Alvah Hunt, 1846 November 7 (Box 8, Folder 698)
  - ALS, Thurlow Weed to Alvah Hunt; results of election, 1846 November 11 (Box 8, Folder 699)
  - ALS, M.R. Waite to E. Lane; Bissell railroad case, 1847 February 3 (Box 8, Folder 700)
  - ALS, Louis McLane to V.H. Boyd; inability to secure promotion for Boyd in War Department, 1847 March 2 (Box 8, Folder 701)
  - ALS, A. Stevenson to Mrs. Marriott; family, friends, gossip, 1847 March 31 (Box 8, Folder 702)
  - ALS, Thurlow Weed to Alvah Hunt; compromise ticket, 1847 May 8 (Box 8, Folder 703)
  - ALS, R.W. McClelland to John Y. Mason; recommendation of midshipman, 1847 June 4 (Box 8, Folder 704)
  - ALS, George P. Marsh (diplomat) to [?]; payment of money, 1847 June 9 (Box 8, Folder 705)
  - ALS, Jacob Thompson (Sec. of Interior) to [?]; regarding who he supports politically, 1847 June 22 (Box 8, Folder 706)
  - ALS, Thurlow Weed to Alvah Hunt; local political matters, 1847 June 26 (Box 8, Folder 707)
  - ALS, W.L. Marcy to Reuben Wethers; financial matters with bank, 1847 June 27 (Box 8, Folder 708)
  - ALS, Weed to Alvah Hunt regarding Prindle's actions, 1847 September 25 (Box 8, Folder 709)
  - ALS, Thurlow Weed to Alvah Hunt; areas of New York backing deal, 1847 October 7 (Box 8, Folder 710)
  - ALS, Weed to Alvah Hunt; anti-rent convention, 1847 October 10 (Box 8, Folder 711)
  - ALS, Thurlow Weed to Alvah Hunt; meetings with Fill more, Morgan, 1847 November 16 (Box 8, Folder 712)
  - ALS, Horace Greeley to Alvah Hunt; decision to back Scott for President, 1847 November 17 (Box 8, Folder 713)
  - ALS, Seward to Alvah Hunt; canals, recommendations, 1847 November 20 (Box 8, Folder 714)
  - ALS, Seward to Alvah Hunt; prospect of Clay as candidate, 1847 December 3 (Box 8, Folder 715)
  - ALS, Thurlow Weed to Alvah Hunt; recommends John C. Clark, despairs of Clay, 1847 December 12 (Box 8, Folder 716)
  - ALS, Thurlow Weed to (?) regarding coming meeting with Hunt, 1848 April 21 (Box 8, Folder 717)
  - ALS, W. Hunt to (?); possible candidacy for Senate, 1848 December 14 (Box 8, Folder 718)
  - ALS, W. Hunt to Alvah Hunt; removal of Wright, 1848 December 14 (Box 8, Folder 719)
  - ALS, W. Hunt to Alvah Hunt regarding W. Hunt's campaign, 1848 December 25 (Box 8, Folder 720)
  - ALS, Gov. Hamilton Fish to Treasurer; question of keeping or returning letter, 1849 January 11 (Box 8, Folder 721)
  - ALS, W. Hunt to Alvah Hunt; regarding Mr. Jordon, 1849 January 13 (Box 8, Folder 722)
  - ALS, W. Hunt to A. Hunt; letter to Morgan Johnson, 1849 January 14 (Box 8, Folder 723)
  - ALS, W. Hunt to Alvah Hunt; news of loss of support for Seward, 1849 January 27 (Box 8, Folder 724)
  - ALS, Seward to Alvah Hunt; members of Congress who have been kind to him, 1849 January 28 (Box 8, Folder 725)
  - ALS, W. Hunt to Alvah Hunt; copy of letter to clear name after comptroller incident, 1849 January 29 (Box 8, Folder 726)
  - ALS, Hamilton Fish to (?); invitation to meeting, 1849 January 31 (Box 8, Folder 727)
  - ALS, W. Hunt to Alvah Hunt; canal tolls, assuming office, 1849 February 11 (Box 8, Folder 728)
  - ALS, J.M. Mason to E.M. Preston (Sec. of Navy)- regarding recommendation of Edward Tidhale, 1849 March 9 (Box 8, Folder 729)
  - ALS, W. Seward to Alvah Hunt; Thanks for letter about V.P.'s allying bargain, 1849 March 17 (Box 8, Folder 730)
  - ALS, H. Fish to Alvah Hunt; Question about which man Hunt wants appointed, 1849 May 1 (Box 8, Folder 731)
  - ALS, Thurlow Weed to Millard Fillmore and others; open letter concerning establishment of Whig journal, 1849 July 20 (Box 8, Folder 732)
  - ALS, Joseph R. Hawley. to Coolidge; trip to Wesleyan, Trinity; discussion of anti-slavery bill, Calhoun's speech, 1849 August 14 (Box 8, Folder 733)
  - ALS, Seward to Alvah Hunt; thanks for forwarding Patton's letter, 1849 August 26 (Box 8, Folder 734)
  - ALS, Franklin Pierce to Capt. Slocum; request of soldier for back pay, 1849 September 27 (Box 8, Folder 735)
  - ALS, Thurlow Weed to Alvah Hunt; poor state of affairs in New York, 1849 October 28 (Box 8, Folder 736)
  - ALS, Hamilton Fish to Treasurer; potential in New York, 1849 October 30 (Box 8, Folder 737)
  - ALS, Thurlow Weed to Alvah Hunt; present state of elections, 1849 November 4 (Box 8, Folder 738)
  - ALS, Abbott Laurence to James Savage; feeling of Great Britain toward U.S, 1849 November 7 (Box 8, Folder 739)
  - DS, Application of L.A. Pratt for life insurance policy, 1849 November 11 (Box 8, Folder 740)
  - ALS, William Seward to Alvah Hunt; congratulations on successful election, 1849 November 15 (Box 8, Folder 741)
  - ALS, William Seward to Alvah Hunt; congratulatory, 1849 November 16 (Box 8, Folder 742)
  - Diary of Capt. Henry Shembre-Photostatic Copy; Photostat of news clipping regarding diary and death of Shombre, 1849 (Box 8, Folder 743)
  - ALS, William Seward to Alvah Hunt; trouble with Southern extremes, 1850 January 11 (Box 9, Folder 744)
  - ALS, Hamilton Fish to Alvah Hunt; refusal of Kelly, 1850 January 21 (Box 9, Folder 745)
  - ALS, Thurlow Weed to Alvah Hunt; enclosed blanks to fill out, 1850 January 22 (Box 9, Folder 746)
  - ALS, Washington Hunt to Alvah Hunt; request interview (with answer from Hunt), 1850 January 27 (Box 9, Folder 747)
  - ALS, C.A. Bacon to Alvah Hunt; letter of introduction, 1850 February 7 (Box 9, Folder 748)
  - ALS, James M. Banks to Hamilton Fish concerning suspect for burglaries, 1850 February 9 (Box 9, Folder 749)
  - ALS, George W. Gray to Alvah Hunt; explanation of three letters sent from Fish's office, 1850 March 20 (Box 9, Folder 750)
  - Diary of Overland Journey to California in from Journal of Ezra Bourne (with editor's comments) Typed Copy, 1850 March 26-August (Box 9, Folder 751)
  - ALS, William Seward to Alvah Hunt; state of affairs with Congress and Administration, 1850 April 12 (Box 9, Folder 752)
  - ALS, Hamilton Fish to Alvah Hunt; case of Nash, 1850 April 18 (Box 9, Folder 753)
  - ALS, Thurlow Weed to Alvah Hunt; Clay's Compromise of 1850, 1850 May 18 (Box 9, Folder 754)
  - ALS, Hamilton Fish to Alvah Hunt; Sectionalism, Compromise, 1850 May 24 (Box 9, Folder 755)
  - ALS, Lewis Cass to R. Rantoul; money raising for political matters, 1850 July 1 (Box 9, Folder 756)